Guide to the Stanford University, Center for Computer Assisted Research in the Humanities at Stanford, records SC1280
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Center for Computer Assisted Research in the Humanities at Stanford, records
1976-2003
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
McBride, Jerry L.
Stanford University. Center for Computer Assisted Research in the Humanities
SC1280
1.75 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Unless otherwise indicated, materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1984, the Center for Computer Assisted Research in the Humanities (CCARH) is engaged in the developement of large databases of musical and textual materials for applications in research, teaching, and performance.
Scope and Contents
Records consist of music software manuals in both print and electronic formats.
Humanities -- Research.; Musicology.; McBride, Jerry L.; Stanford University. Center for Computer Assisted Research in the Humanities
- Records
  - Software Manuals (print)
    - MUP, 1997 (Box 1)
    - DARMS reference manual, 1976-06 (Box 1)
    - SMDL Working Group, 1985-1990 (Box 1)
    - Computer-based Education Research Library (CERL): The Interactive Music System User's Manual, 1987-01 (Box 1)
    - Computertoepassingen in de muziekwetenschap, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Computertoepassingen in de muziekwetenschap afbeeldingen, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Computertoepassingen in de muziekwetenschap practicumboek, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Software Manuals (computer media & audio)
    - Pratt Green Trust/Stainer & Bell, "HymnQuest 2000" (London), 1997, 2000; 2.1; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 2)
    - Blombach, Ann, "MacGamut 2000" (US, Canada; demo), 2.2; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 2)
    - Wiering, Frans, "Pietro Aaron: 4 Treatises on music theory" (Utrecht), 2003; 2.3; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 2)
    - JLR Group, "Musical instruments", 1996; 2.4; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 2)
    - Midisoft "Sound Explorer", 1995; 2.5; 1 optical disc(s) (cd) (Box 2)
      Scope and Contents
      Smorgasboard of period tools
    - Yamaha Performance Demo, undated; 2.6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Yamaha DX7 Programming Instructions, undated; 2.7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2)
    - Hamel, Keith, "NoteWriter 2.88", 1988-1996; 2.8.1, 2.8.2; 2 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - Perkins, Leeman, "RENARC", undated; 2.9; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - Ferkova, Eva, "Slovak Academy of Sciences, Bratislava", undated; 2.10; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - L[?], Jee, "ES3", undated; 2.11; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - Griffin, Thomas, "Gazetta di Napoli (1)", undated; 2.12; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - Griffin, Thomas, "Gazetta di Napoli (2)", undated; 2.13; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - Griffin, Thomas, "Diario di Roma", undated; 2.14; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - Haas, Mac, "Chatull gadol (Big Cat)" (1), undated; 2.15; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - Haas, Mac, "Chatull gadol (Big Cat)" (2), undated; 2.16; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - Appleton, Jon, "Dartmouth Music Courseware", undated; 2.17; 1 floppy disk(s) (3.5 inch) (Box 2)
    - Palmer, David, "Renaissance music facsimile software", undated; 2.18; 1 floppy disk(s) (5.25 inch) (Box 2)
    - Perkins, Leeman, "RENARC", undated; 2.19; 1 floppy disk(s) (5.25 inch) (Box 2)
    - Ferklova, Eva, "Slovak Academy of Sciences", undated; 2.20; 1 floppy disk(s) (5.25 inch) (Box 2)